[{"id": "58f5677333a95c66dc4fe76b", "question": "What are pouched animals called?", "answer": "Marsupials", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f9", "question": "In which 1998 movie did the main character said \"You got the wrong guy. I'm the Dude, man.\"?", "answer": "The Big Lebowski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8cf", "question": "What basketball hall-of-famer was nicknamed \"Wilt the Stilt\"?", "answer": "Wilt Chamberlain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a67b90aac110e416707e", "question": "In \"Alice in Wonderland\", who did Alice see taking tea under a tree?", "answer": "Mad Hatter and March Hare", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba73", "question": "What Latin phrase is used meaning \u201can attorney representing a client for free\u201d?", "answer": "Pro bono", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a6f720565ad31a57c7e3", "question": "What is considered the turning point of World War II in Europe?", "answer": "Battle of Stalingrad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfa93cf3977a46e7ce447", "question": "The Statue of Liberty was a gift resulting from the diplomatic relationship between the United States and what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c389877e98cb97778995", "question": "Which country has a presidential office known as \"the Pink House\"?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975b", "question": "Who plays the last man on Earth in I Am Legend?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c785", "question": "What English engineer is credited with inventing the seat belt?", "answer": "George Cayley", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339568", "question": "Who play the burglars in, Home Alone?", "answer": "Joe Pesci and Daniel Stern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2dd", "question": "What year was actor Stan Laurel born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940a", "question": "What was the nickname given to the mechanical sharks created for the movie \"Jaws\"?", "answer": "Bruce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0d", "question": "Who was Anne of Green Gables' best friend?", "answer": "Diana Barry", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339067", "question": "Which children's character was created by Mary Tourtel?", "answer": "Rupert Bear", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad95", "question": "What WWII figure was known as \"Old Blood and Guts\"?", "answer": "George Patton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133befd", "question": "How many players are there on a standard soccer team on field?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a1826c0f9723ab15cb3a", "question": "Who was the first honorary citizen of the U.S.?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af6f", "question": "Used to complete the first transcontinental railway, the last spike was made of what material?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa24", "question": "In which US state is Cornell University?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc11c0469bb8041d07a079", "question": "What is the name of a popular Italian orange and vanilla flavored liqueur?", "answer": "Tuaca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbaed870738315b1fb74e30", "question": "What spell was used to trick the Goblet in \"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\"?", "answer": "Confundus Charm", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a728cb56bcd28c11938328a", "question": "What is the capital of Delaware?", "answer": "Dover", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59774305284458f1d7854424", "question": "Who was the first host of \"America's Got Talent\"?", "answer": "Regis Philbin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766b5eec85e375820b287", "question": "Captain Henry Morgan used what island as a base of buccaneer operations?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a263", "question": "Alanis Morrisette appeared on what 1980's TV show?\u00a0", "answer": "You Can't Do that On Television", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a990", "question": "What city named its airport after Galileo Galilei?", "answer": "Pisa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f2b801dd7bf43be5e812", "question": "What celebrity chef authored mystery novels before they got famous?", "answer": "Anthony Bourdain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb1", "question": "Which ingredient provides the red color in a Tequila Sunrise?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb44", "question": "At what university did Tiger Woods play collegiate golf for two years before turning pro?", "answer": "Stanford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5937ea0608d98002fdd6339e", "question": "Which Stephen King novel is set at the \"Overlook Hotel\"?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00f", "question": "What two metal bands are honored on Beavis and Butt-head's usual t-shirts?", "answer": "AC/DC and Metallica", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b487", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f2", "question": "What color hair does the \"Mona Lisa\" have?", "answer": "Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6c", "question": "Which epic film was based on a novel by Lew Wallace?", "answer": "Ben Hur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339208", "question": "What pop star posed naked and pregnant on the August 2006 cover of Harper's Bazaar?", "answer": "Britney Spears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd82125d0de9af39e9d46a3", "question": "Who founded the first McDonald's?", "answer": "Richard and Maurice McDonald", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12ecee39efa6330e0fed4", "question": "Which country has the largest rhino population?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908a", "question": "What well known Russian author was also a doctor?", "answer": "Anton Chekhov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa48", "question": "What is the capital of Aruba?", "answer": "Oranjestad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc5546ce05a3942286f3b", "question": "What is a pli\u00e9 in ballet?", "answer": "Bending at the knees", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c1", "question": "Tristram is the main town of which RPG game?", "answer": "Diablo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ae863427f28483af1e7fdc9", "question": "What was the last imperial dynasty of China?", "answer": "Qing Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015f87dfe83fe1f2a824c2e", "question": "In which ancient South Asian language is the text of The Vedas written?", "answer": "Sanskrit - The religious poems originated in northwestern India in 1500-1000 BCE.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f8", "question": "The infamous glitch Pokemon \"missingno\" is found in the games Pokemon Red and what else?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdffcc31cf6db9ac4808d03", "question": "What is the longest bridge in the San Francisco Bay Area?", "answer": "San Mateo-Hayward Bridge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ec", "question": "What color is a Livestrong bracelet?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d7", "question": "What is added to cognac to make a Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "White creme de menthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8b", "question": "Maseru is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Lesotho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59524338736d4be723796b67", "question": "How many of the same item can you get in the term \"Bakers Dozen\"?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a1c612f2a7826b9b8715", "question": "What milk is Pecorino cheese made from?", "answer": "Ewe's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c218", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601370411381754895396380", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", what is the name of the pizza delivery?", "answer": "Little Nero's Pizza -- It is a parody of Little Ceasar's Pizza.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d992308b8581f80b092b3", "question": "Which rock and roll pioneer passed away on March 18, 2017, at the age of 90?", "answer": "Chuck Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c7c", "question": "What is Indiana Jones' daytime occupation?", "answer": "Professor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d97ee08b8581f80b092ac", "question": "Which campaign was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 2017 for its work to promote the full implementation of the Treaty on Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons?", "answer": "The International Campaign to Abolish Nuclear Weapons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323302bf195a31e15d7396", "question": "Who is Woody Woodpecker's girlfriend?", "answer": "Winnie Woodpecker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba18", "question": "What does the abbreviation NASA stand for?", "answer": "National Aeronautics and Space Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a9a120565ad31a57c808", "question": "Who issued the \"Emancipation Proclamation\"?", "answer": "President Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395d3", "question": "In The Simpsons, how are the out-of-control robots at Itchy & Scratchy Land stopped?", "answer": "Flash photography", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388c8", "question": "Who created the character Hercule Poirot?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339591", "question": "What is outlawed in the town in the movie \"Footloose\"?", "answer": "Dancing and rock music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80c", "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9fa", "question": "What metal do you get from Hematite?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c0", "question": "What \"island\", the southern-most tip of Brooklyn, has three miles of famous boardwalk?", "answer": "Coney Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338903", "question": "What Ian Fleming novel's title is the nickname of the character Francisco Scaramanga?", "answer": "The Man with the Golden Gun", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a0f", "question": "Who is the richest character in \"The Wind in the Willows\"?", "answer": "Mr. Toad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b216", "question": "Who was assassinated by Yigal Amir?", "answer": "Yitzhak Rabin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff7beb32b316f4693fb6792", "question": "How many characters are in the Korean alphabet/Hangul", "answer": "24", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea2", "question": "Who began forty-five straight lines of his poem \"Howl\" with the word \"who\"?", "answer": "Allen Ginsberg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af7", "question": "Which character killed Captain Ahab?", "answer": "Moby-Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59068023ff9c0647b50a808a", "question": "Which British actor played the role of Spider-Man in the 2016 film \"Captain America: Civil War\"?", "answer": "Tom Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b4a", "question": "What rock band is led by Bob Dylan's son, Jakob?", "answer": "The Wallflowers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bb62364247bf200fb8a3", "question": "Who was disqualified after winning the 1976 British Grand Prix?", "answer": "James Hunt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e60", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Stewie Griffin?", "answer": "Seth MacFarlane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f32", "question": "What is the infirmity of Jake Barnes, the protagonist of \"The Sun Also Rises\"?", "answer": "He's impotent from a war wound", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62f", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for Massachusetts?", "answer": "MA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7d", "question": "What is the capital of Azerbaijan?", "answer": "Baku", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb6f07e83c707845b212c", "question": "What\u2019s the difference between green and black olives?", "answer": "Ripeness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe69dda20565ad31a57c77e", "question": "What is the largest surviving Roman triumphal arch in the world?", "answer": "Arch of Constantine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a69220565ad31a57c7db", "question": "What was the name of British General Charles Cornwallis' dogs?", "answer": "Mars and Jupiter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd5", "question": "Pretzel and potato chip company Snyder's is based out of what Pennsylvania city?", "answer": "Hanover", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59523dc2736d4be723796b47", "question": "What year did the last Province or Territory join Canada?", "answer": "1999", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015dfb3fe83fe1f2a824b7d", "question": "What ancestor of brass knuckles did ancient warriors use?", "answer": "Cestus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a801", "question": "Which US state's flag is the only one with a Union Jack on it?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392a2", "question": "What character did Christopher Lloyd play in the movie \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit?", "answer": "Judge Doom", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e2", "question": "What year was the first book of the \"Bourne Trilogy\" series first published?", "answer": "1980", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bd", "question": "What name is given to the metal bars running across the neck of a guitar?", "answer": "Frets", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab98", "question": "What Australian state shares a nickname with the US state of Florida?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9087f01dd7bf43be5e884", "question": "What is the most prominent crater on the Moon?", "answer": "Tycho", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a280", "question": "Which UK Label is associated with a dog named Nipper?", "answer": "HMV", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b596", "question": "Which building has been nicknamed \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "GE Building", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339074", "question": "Which 1965 science fiction novel featured the Houses of Corrino, Harkonnen, and Atreides?", "answer": "Dune", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994d", "question": "What sitcom star\u2019s parents were named Morty and Helen on his TV show?", "answer": "Jerry Seinfeld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93c", "question": "The phrase \"banana republic\" was first coined by O. Henry in reference to what country?", "answer": "Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395b0", "question": "Which Simpsons character says he was once a watch commander at Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "Abe Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e93747ccba3ffe45786c6", "question": "Who invented the \"Miner's Lamp\"?", "answer": "Humphry Davy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a0c", "question": "Who played Khan in \"Star Trek II: The Wrath of Khan\"?", "answer": "Ricardo Montalban", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b07", "question": "What Jane Austen novel was rewritten in 2009 to include zombies?", "answer": "Pride and Prejudice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bedd", "question": "In the game of chess, which piece has the most freedom to move?", "answer": "The queen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bb35b0d2627b8fe95581bea", "question": "What YouTube Red TV series is based on \"The Karate Kid\" films and stars Ralph Macchio and William Zabka,", "answer": "Cobra Kai", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596df8c6f0cc2631d16a3c62", "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399cb", "question": "What Norwegian band hit number 1 in the US in 1985 with the song \"Take On Me\"?", "answer": "a-Ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c095", "question": "In France what kind of nuts are noisette?", "answer": "Hazelnuts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfb", "question": "Chuck Taylor was the first endorser of what popular brand of shoes?", "answer": "Converse All Stars", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a53c", "question": "What four US states begin with the letter \"W\"?", "answer": "Washington, West Virginia, Wisconsin and Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c487", "question": "What is the common name for the infection known as \"tinea pedis\"?", "answer": "Athlete's foot", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a569", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Keystone State\"?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea7", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Chip, Dot, Ditto and Trixie?", "answer": "Hi and Lois", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc3dd6ce05a3942286f28", "question": "Which member of Fleetwood Mac was inducted into the Rock & Roll Hall of Fame twice?", "answer": "Stevie Nicks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bbb", "question": "In Roman mythology who killed Remus?", "answer": "Romulus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7b", "question": "What slang term for the stomach is the highest-scoring ailment in the game \"Operation\"?", "answer": "The Breadbasket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba16", "question": "What sport's Hall of Fame is located in Cooperstown?", "answer": "Baseball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071c353745b36be73039c9", "question": "Who recruits Tony to the F.D.A. in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "Mason Savoy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffcfbd49dc5ec6cd98a8318", "question": "Who painted \"The Starry Night\"?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81bdbd0de9af39e9d467d", "question": "What was Martin Van Buren nickname?", "answer": "Old Kinderhook", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974e", "question": "What are the names of the members of Pentatonix?", "answer": "Scott, Mitch, Avi, Kirsten, and Kevin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada4", "question": "In what US state was the outlaw Jesse James born?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf2", "question": "Bishkek is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Kyrgystan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6012152463c99d48cd169ae7", "question": "What did Einstein reportedly do to stay focused?", "answer": "Play music -- His wife Elsa said that when he was struggling with a theory he would play a few chords on the piano to focus.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9444574a5ce6b56b8247", "question": "What was Agatha Christie's second husband's profession?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339514", "question": "Who voiced Pinocchio in Disney's 1940 movie by the same name?", "answer": "Dickie Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b114", "question": "What Spanish explorer became the first governor of Puerto Rico in 1508?", "answer": "Juan Ponce de Leon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c961", "question": "Which planet was discovered in 1846?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac98", "question": "Which Italian city did Christopher Columbus claim he was born in?", "answer": "Genoa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b429", "question": "What year did Malawi declare independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1964", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c767", "question": "What blood cell deficiency gets its name from the Greek meaning \"being without blood\"?", "answer": "Anemia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133923e", "question": "What superhero is known as the \"Caped Crusader\"?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfda99616e6c6d4eba4f7", "question": "On the hit show \"Seinfeld\" what was Kramer's first name? ", "answer": "Cosmo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5a", "question": "What year was \"Cirque du Soleil\" founded?", "answer": "1984", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe0e386fcbed638185eaa22", "question": "What U.S. state is nicknamed \"The Sooner State\"?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afac", "question": "What was Sunday, January 30th 1972, generally remembered as in Ireland?", "answer": "Bloody Sunday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6661ca5bfecdd737e0865", "question": "Where is Apple Inc. headquartered?", "answer": "Cupertino, California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee6", "question": "What two colors make the color green?", "answer": "Blue and yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b4f49076251badbeac2", "question": "The month of July was named after whom?", "answer": "Julius Caesar-- It was named by the Roman Senate in honor of the Roman general and statesman, it being the\u00a0month\u00a0of his birth.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba1d", "question": "What was unusual about Dizzy Gillespie's trumpet?", "answer": "The bell was bent upwards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cc", "question": "What type of instrument is a Celesta?", "answer": "Keyboard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe698ff20565ad31a57c73e", "question": "The first-ever ticker-tape parade was thrown in celebration of what event?", "answer": "The dedication of the Statue of Liberty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54a", "question": "The mouth of what bay is located between Cape Charles and Cape Henry?", "answer": "Chesapeake Bay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c264", "question": "What constitutes 12 percent of an egg's weight?", "answer": "The shell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ae", "question": "In what city would you find Gorky Park?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afad", "question": "Off of which European coastline was the \"Battle of Trafalgar\" fought?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393cd", "question": "Who sang \"Singing in the Rain\"?", "answer": "Gene Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a611", "question": "Which area of Romania is known as the home of Dracula?", "answer": "Transylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5f1b6ce05a3942286e3d", "question": "Elton John wrote the song \"Philadelphia Freedom\" as a tribute to what tennis star?", "answer": "Billie Jean King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e2fffe83fe1f2a824ba4", "question": "What was unique about the Doolittle Raid against Japan?", "answer": "The bombers took off from an aircraft carrier.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6a2106c0f9723ab15cb3e", "question": "How many constellations are there in the sky?", "answer": "48 traditional Western constellations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339112", "question": "Who wrote the 1897 novel \"The Invisible Man\"?", "answer": "H. G. Wells", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad9e232e748bb36357acdf9", "question": "What year did Alfred Hitchcock release his first American made film?", "answer": "1940", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f88", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"The Piano\"?", "answer": "Anna Paquin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8838ec223966ae8f881c", "question": "What is the name of the legendary videogame designer who created the Mario franchise?", "answer": "Shigeru Miyamoto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a593", "question": "Which US state is referred to as the \"Silver State\"?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75d", "question": "What is the deepest lake in the world?", "answer": "Lake Baikal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afba", "question": "Who was the last Viceroy to India?", "answer": "Lord Mountbatten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d9a6708b8581f80b092bc", "question": "What did the United Nations General Assembly designate 2017 as?", "answer": "International Year of Sustainable Tourism for Development", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a1db20565ad31a57c7a8", "question": "Who popularized the white wedding dress?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd18b3629d03ab85b632b2f", "question": "What is a female turkey called?", "answer": "Hen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a1", "question": "What award winning 1994 Tim Robbins movie was shot at the Ohio State Reformatory?", "answer": "The Shawshank Redemption", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a770", "question": "Before being renamed, what was Mumbai called?", "answer": "Bombay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b367", "question": "Who married Prince Albert of Saxe-Coburg and Gotha?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a510", "question": "Which two independent states exist within Italy's borders?", "answer": "Vatican City and San Marino", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff667ec52a821ff76ae8b00", "question": "The myth that carrots improve your vision is rooted in a propaganda campaign from which war?", "answer": "World War II (To keep the use of radar a secret. British officials launched a campaign stating eating carrots improved night vision.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c783", "question": "What two mammals spend their entire lives in the water?", "answer": "Whales and manatees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f3", "question": "What is the name the Australian film based on the life of pianist David Helfgott?", "answer": "Shine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971df0c89261e916c8e09a5", "question": "What is the name of Batman's Butler?", "answer": "Alfred", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea2", "question": "What magazine ran the famous cover of a very pregnant Demi Moore in the buff?", "answer": "Vanity Fair", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c631", "question": "Which planet is the hottest in our Solar System?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab14cebaab681b09292178", "question": "Which Formula One world champion assisted Honda in the final design stages of the NSX?", "answer": "Ayrton Senna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc101ec223966ae8f8863", "question": "The 2016 Cavaliers defeated which NBA team to win Cleveland\u2019s first title?", "answer": "Golden State Warriors", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94e17ccba3ffe45786d9", "question": "What language was the first English-like data processing language?", "answer": "FLOW-MATIC", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc0a8ec223966ae8f885d", "question": "What guards the Ark of the Covenant in \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc2f6facee580c7f8fd1e5d", "question": "What does \"M&Ms\" stand for in the candy with the same name?", "answer": "Mars & Murrie's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b0", "question": "What is the 1919 Jallianwahla Bagh massacre also known as?", "answer": "The Amritsar massacre", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c1", "question": "How many horns does the average African black rhino have?", "answer": "Two", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58c8a50e90aac110e4167070", "question": "What is Homer Simpson\u2019s beer of choice?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c790877e98cb977789d1", "question": "Where will you find \"The Great White Way\"?", "answer": "Broadway, New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398c3", "question": "What instrument does Rolf play on \"The Muppet Show\"?", "answer": "Piano", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a695", "question": "What is the official language of Guyana?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b695", "question": "What color is the legendary Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7cb", "question": "What republic is located between Lithuania and Estonia?", "answer": "Latvia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397fb", "question": "Who had a 1982 No.1 hit with \"Happy Talk\"?", "answer": "Captain Sensible", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91e", "question": "What is the body of water that surrounds a castle called?", "answer": "A moat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b6", "question": "Who did Abraham Lincoln face in a series of debates in 1858?", "answer": "Stephen Douglas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef32ed6ce05a3942286e00", "question": "How many U.S. states are needed to ratify an amendment for it to become part of the constitution?", "answer": "Three-fourths", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c98c9d816e292245c2d", "question": "What kind of cans did Andy Warhol famously paint?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup Cans\u00a0is a work of art consisting of 32 canvases, each painted with a Campbell's Soup can.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8c", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is James Smith?", "answer": "LL Cool J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ec", "question": "The cerebrum is the largest part of what organ?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015eca3fe83fe1f2a824c05", "question": "Which serving president was the first to have his photograph taken inside the White House?", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d1158c4fea7fe947a22267", "question": "Banjul is the capital of which country?", "answer": "The Gambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d3", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The G.I. General\"?", "answer": "Omar Bradley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b88621d8c1817608d53f2", "question": "Choux and filo are types of what?", "answer": "Pastry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6662aa5bfecdd737e0866", "question": "How long are the white dashed lines that divide lanes on U.S. roads?", "answer": "10 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77359eec85e375820b305", "question": "Which lake crosses the borders of Vermont, New York, and Canada?", "answer": "Lake Champlain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be65", "question": "What is the more common name for a \"double-eagle\" on a gold hole?", "answer": "An albatross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f5", "question": "What size engine did the first Volkswagen Golf GTI model have?", "answer": "1.6 L", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b4e601dd7bf43be5e7c9", "question": "What is the only US state with an official jelly?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1dd9b5a031299b74573e", "question": "What century did the Icelandic Vikings first reach the island of Newfoundland?", "answer": "11th Century", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339612", "question": "In which movie does Woody Allen awaken 200 years in the future?", "answer": "Sleeper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c6", "question": "What is the common name for the animal classified as \"Ursus arctos\"?", "answer": "Brown bear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d06ca9870e6f05ba600854", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Moneychangers\"?", "answer": "Arthur Hailey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "596761c92b59efe0e9417ea6", "question": "The 13 stripes on the US Flag represent what?", "answer": "The 13 original colonies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a79a", "question": "What is the capital of Canada?", "answer": "Ottawa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133935b", "question": "Who played the role of Sue Ann Nivens on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Betty White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d9", "question": "Who was Martina Navratilova's usual ladies doubles partner in the 1980's?\u00a0", "answer": "Pam Shriver\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5921fdf9a4edfd43a087adcb", "question": "Disney's 2013 film \"Frozen\" was inspired by which fairy tale?", "answer": "The Snow Queen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec247b8dc25ca9e12ef638", "question": "Cinnabar is the most common source for which compound?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9d9", "question": "Which African country had its capital transferred to Abuja?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c77b", "question": "What reptile's image is the logo of a popular French sportswear company?", "answer": "The crocodile's", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d7", "question": "Luzon and Mindanao are the two largest islands of what country?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f32", "question": "Which band member of Mother Love Bone died of drug overdose?", "answer": "Andrew Wood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc36", "question": "What basketball superstar is nicknamed \"His Airness\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda5", "question": "What is the name for the arrow-like projectiles fired by a crossbow?", "answer": "Bolts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b937", "question": "What do you have to be in the NBA to win the Eddie Gottlieb trophy?", "answer": "Rookie of the Year", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea42e7ff048f679a45ab7c", "question": "What body part does a butterfly use for tasting?", "answer": "Hind feet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e9a606d333868d34d757", "question": "During World War II, the U.S. purchase more than 150 million pounds of what to feed its troops?", "answer": "SPAM", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dfb", "question": "What \"Fantasy Island\" actor ended up committing suicide?", "answer": "Herve Villechaize", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c60", "question": "George Lucas' first full feature film, \"THX 1138\" was released in what year?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3426ce05a3942286f21", "question": "Who is Angelina Jolie's father?", "answer": "Jon Voight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339021", "question": "Whose autobiography's main title is \"True\"?", "answer": "Martin Kemp", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c6", "question": "Which state is home to Okefenokee National Wildlife Refuge?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "592eaf1cf83302ff91e46490", "question": "What city was nicknamed \"The Paris of the West\"?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a1a21b12f2a7826b9b8718", "question": "What sport would you be playing if the score was deuce?", "answer": "Tennis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab963a86faa38a764be51d", "question": "What was the original cost of the first Ford Model T, sold in 1909?", "answer": "$825", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc4", "question": "Who was the first American in space?", "answer": "Alan Shepard", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99b3e21a8909e5c332d29", "question": "Who played the main female character in the 1939 film \"Destry Rides Again\"?", "answer": "Marlene Dietrich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d51", "question": "What is 007 enemy Dr. No's first name?", "answer": "Julius", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab96a986faa38a764be521", "question": "Despite not being the first company to make a minivan, which company introduced the first successful mass-produced minivan in 1983?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a535", "question": "What is the largest lake found completely within the United States?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d2db2596a59cbdfbd394", "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab3", "question": "How many secret herbs and spices are in the original recipe chicken at KFC?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefa", "question": "In what country was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339028", "question": "In Arthurian legend, who is the illegitemate son of Sir Lancelot?", "answer": "Galahad", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c3813815febcc896f9279", "question": "What is the eigth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Scorpio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf1", "question": "The Albert Canal links Liege with which city?", "answer": "Antwerp", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd6", "question": "Who played the title character in the film \"The Omega Man\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a889", "question": "What two US state capitals are named for people who were executed?", "answer": "Raleigh and St. Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f77", "question": "What was Gladys Knight's backing band?", "answer": "The Pips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c6440775fa611bce67d0", "question": "Singapore's Marina Bay Sands hotel is home to the world's highest what?", "answer": "Swimming pool -- The hotel has on its rooftop an enormous infinity pool.  At 650 feet, it is the world's  highest swimming pool.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cf", "question": "What are the last names of the two Steves who founded \"Apple Computers\"?", "answer": "Jobs and Wozniak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b50201dd7bf43be5e7cb", "question": "What is the main ingredient in the British dish laverbread?", "answer": "Seaweed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601371c0138175489539638d", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him massive royalties. According to Anka, he received $200 every time the song was played.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a476", "question": "What African country was formerly known as Northern Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zambia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c1", "question": "Which 1954 film won eight Oscars?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7667deec85e375820b281", "question": "In what country would you celebrate \"Carnival\"?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c496877e98cb977789a1", "question": "In which Canadian province do the Appalachian Mountains end?", "answer": "Newfoundland and Labrador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339201", "question": "In what movie does Redfoot flick his cigarette into the face of McManus?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339412", "question": "On the \"Abbey Road\" album cover, which member of the Beatles is on the far left?", "answer": "George Harrison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde519ec6c6b019850c9a90", "question": "Herbert Hoover became well known when he organized relief efforts for what country after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77ce4924f0f7a362efd545", "question": "A-ha and Edward Grieg hail from what country ", "answer": "Norway", "category": "entertainment"}]